

# Zaid Maqsood

## **Software Specialist**

172, Banni Manzil J.B shah marg, chinch Bunder road, Mumbai, Maharashtra

Mobile +917303063848

Email: zaidmaqsood58@gmail.com

### Summary

Provide technical support and customer service to clients. As a Technical support engineer I am committed to diagnosing, reproducing, and fixing customer software and hardware issues. To assist customer with problem isolation and resolution. If requested, escalate the customer's case to a subject matter expert.

# Work experience

#### March 2018 - May 2019

#### **Software Specialist**

#### eClinicalWorks

- Studied front end as well as backend part of the EMR/EHR software solution and to implement new features on the existing solution.
- Testing and further development of the module. Languages involved: JAVA, XML, JSP, MySQL, MsSQL, Web Services, Tomcat, and FileZilla.
- Good knowledge of Communication protocols- ANSI-X12 (Electronic Data Interchange) helps in debugging and further understanding which data can be transferred electronically.
- Installation and implementations of PLSQL based business reports in the EMR application.
- Part of Release Management team to approve and provide class file, jsp file and Database fixes
- Perform upgrade, patches as well as install EMR/EHR software.
- Working on client server, locally hosted and cloud server environment to resolve the issues.
- Interacting and coordinating with all the stakeholders, involved in projects across all the stages of implementation cycle.
- Worked on JIRA tool for identifying and reporting bug, troubleshoot and test incident, tracking and resolution management.
- Handle cases/escalations, Responsible for testing the software and reporting the issue abide
  by the prescribed norms.
- Provided technical assistance to internal team as well as clients with regards to the problem they face when using application
- Complete and detailed documentation of the resolution and the root cause.

#### Jan 2017 - Feb 2018

#### **Technical support Engineer**

#### Qualsoft Systems PVT LTD

- Application Engineer SQL Server, Dot NET, Data Base, IIS.
- Provided technical assistance to client's for the problems faced while using ERP applications
- System Administration and Maintenance of Hardware & Software
- Implementation of SQL Express for SQL database SQL Server Installation, Creation of SQL Database.
- Installation and configuration of Windows based operating systems. (2007/2008/2010).
- Trouble shooting of all types of Hardware and software applications problems.
- Configuring and installing Bio-Metric machine.
- Trouble shooting hardware, software & networking problems. Password creation
- & resetting to end users through remote desktop. Communicate and interact with
- the other team members or colleagues to ensure coordination and cross-training.

## Education

2015 - 2017 Master of Computer Applications

LBHSST'S INSTITUTE OF COMPUTER APPLICATION

Project: Lowest Quote

This project was aimed at developing a Web application that depicts Online Price comparison

website for

Shopping of products and Booking of Flight Tickets and Hotel Booking.

2011 - 2014 Bachelor of Computer Application

K. P. B. Hinduja College

2009 - 2010 H.S.C XIIth

Bhavan's collage Stream -Science

## **Skills**

Hardware/Systems

PC/Server, Admin, Routers, Switches, Windows, Bio-metric Machine

**Databases** 

Ms SQL, MySQL

Languages

C++, SQL, HTML, CSS, Java Script

**Applications** 

Microsoft Office Suite: Word, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint, EMR, ERP

## Personal details:

Father's Name : Mohd Maqsood

Date of Birth : 01st July 1992.

Language known : English, Hindi, Urdu, Marathi.